(MUSIC PLAYING)
(PANTING)
(BEEPING)
- Mama!
- LYRA: We know.
Jyn, gather your things. It's time.
- SAW: Hello?
- Saw, it's Lyra.
It's happened. He's come for us.
You know what to do.
(LOUD HUMMING)
GALEN: Jyn, come here.
Remember, whatever I do,
I do it to protect you.
Say you understand.
I understand.
I love you, Stardust.
I love you, too, Papa.
Galen.
Go.
Jyn.
You know where to go, don't you?
Trust the Force.
(SIGHS)
(PANTING)
You're a hard man to find, Galen.
But farming...
Really? Man of your talents?
It's a peaceful life.
It's lonely, I imagine.
Since Lyra died, yes.
Oh.
Oh...
(EXHALES)
My condolences.
Search the house.
(MECHANICAL VOICES
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
GALEN: What is it you want?
The work has stalled.
I need you to come back.
I won't do it, Krennic.
We were on the verge of greatness.
We were this close
to providing peace
and security for the galaxy.
You're confusing peace with terror.
Well,
you have to start somewhere.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
I'd be of no help, Krennic.
My mind just isn't what it was.
I have trouble remembering.
Even simple things.
Galen...
You're an inspired scientist,
but you're a terrible liar.
Now, I admire the effort.
I really do.
Oh, look, here's Lyra,
back from the dead.
It's a miracle.
(SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
Stop!
(WEAPON WHINES)
Oh, Lyra,
troublesome as ever.
You're not taking him.
No, of course I'm not. I'm taking you all.
You'll all come. You, your child.
You'll all live in comfort.
As hostages.
As heroes of the Empire.
Lyra. Put it down.
Think very carefully.
(BREATH TREMBLING)
- You will never win.
- Do it.
- (WEAPONS FIRING)
- (BOTH GROANING)
- (GASPS)
- Lyra!
Lyra!
They have a child!
Find it!
(JYN PANTING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(MECHANICAL VOICES SPEAKING)
(JYN BREATHING HEAVILY)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(JYN CONTINUES PANTING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
My child!
Come.
We have a long ride ahead of us.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(WATER DRIPPING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(CELL MATE SNORING)
ANNOUNCER ON PA:
Check in security,
cell block 4227.
4227.
(MAN SCREAMING IN PAIN)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
STORMTROOPER 1: TK-62, XX-25900.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER CONTINUES)
(TIVIK PANTING)
I was about to leave.
I came as fast as I could.
I have to get back on board.
Walk with me.
Back to Jedha?
They'll leave without me.
Easy! You have news from Jedha.
Come on.
An Imperial pilot,
one of the cargo drivers
he defected yesterday.
He's telling people
they're making a weapon.
The kyber crystals,
that's what they're for.
What kind of weapon?
- Look, I have to go.
- What kind of weapon?
A planet killer! That's what he called it!
A planet killer?
Someone named Erso sent him.
Some old friend of Saw's.
Galen Erso? Was it?
I don't know!
They were looking for Saw when we left.
- Who else knows about this?
- I have no idea.
It's all falling apart.
Saw's right.
- There's spies everywhere.
- (INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
STORMTROOPER 1: What's all this?
Come on, let's see some scandocs.
Yeah, of course. Just... My gloves.
(GROANS)
- No!
- (INDISTINCT YELLING)
What have you done?
Troopers down. Section 9.
TIVIK: Are you crazy?
I'll never climb out of here. My arm!
STORMTROOPER 2:
Get out of the way.
Move! Move!
Hey. Calm down. Calm down.
- It will be all right.
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
(FIRES WEAPON)
(ALARM BLARING IN THE DISTANCE)
(GRUNTING)
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
Is that him?
He looks kind of different
to how I imagined.
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
(GASPS) Okay.
So you're Saw Gerrera?
Saw Gerrera?
No?
Okay, we're just wasting time
that we don't have.
I need to speak to Saw Gerrera.
I keep telling them.
Before it's too late.
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
We're out here in the middle of nowhere.
We need to get to Jedha City.
What part of "urgent message"
do you guys not understand?
(GRUNTING)
We are all on the same side.
If you just see past
the uniform for a minute.
(CONTINUES SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
(VEHICLE STOPS)
What now?
I don't know. Must be another pickup.
I thought we had everybody.
(DOOR LATCH CLICKS)
(STORMTROOPERS GROANING)
All clear, sir.
Hallik! Liana Hallik!
Her.
You wanna get out of here?
Hey! What about me?
(GRUNTING)
Give me the keys! Give me the keys!
(CONTINUES GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
Congratulations. You are being rescued.
Please do not resist.
(REBEL SOLDIERS
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
REBEL ANNOUNCER: LU-28,
report to maintenance level 4.
(INDISTINCT MECHANICAL CHATTER)
You're currently
calling yourself Liana Hallik.
Is that correct?
Possession of unsanctioned weapons.
Forgery of Imperial documents.
Aggravated assault.
Escape from custody.
Resisting arrest.
Imagine if the Imperial authorities
had found out...
who you really were, Jyn Erso.
That is your given name, is it not?
Jyn Erso, daughter of Galen Erso?
A known Imperial collaborator
in weapons development.
What is this?
MON MOTHMA: It's a chance
for you to make a fresh start.
We think you might be able to help us.
This is Captain Cassian Andor,
Rebel Intelligence.
When was the last time
you were in contact with your father?
15 years ago.
Any idea where he's been all that time?
I like to think he's dead.
Makes things easier.
Easier than what? That he's been a tool
of the Imperial war machine?
I've never had the luxury
of political opinions.
Really?
When was your last contact
with Saw Gerrera?
It's been a long time.
But he'll remember you, though.
Wouldn't he?
He might agree to meet you,
if you came as a friend.
We're up against the clock here, girl,
so if there's nothing to talk about,
we'll just put you back
where we found you.
I was a child.
Saw Gerrera saved my life. He raised me.
But I have no idea where he is.
I haven't seen him in years.
CASSIAN: We know how to find him.
That's not our problem.
What we need is someone
who gets us through the door
without being killed.
You're all rebels, aren't you?
MON MOTHMA: Yes,
but Saw Gerrera is an extremist.
He's been fighting on his own
since he broke with the Rebellion.
His militancy has caused the Alliance
a great many problems.
We have no choice now but to try
and mend that broken trust.
What does this have to do
with my father?
There's an Imperial defector
in Jedha. A pilot.
He's been held by Saw Gerrera.
He's claiming the Emperor
is creating a weapon
with the power to destroy entire planets.
The pilot says
he was sent by your father.
MON MOTHMA:
We need to stop this weapon
before it is finished.
Captain Andor's mission
is to authenticate the pilot's story.
And then, if possible, find your father.
It appears he is critical
to the development
of this super weapon.
Given the gravity of the situation
and your history with Saw,
we're hoping that he will
help us locate your father
and return him
to the Senate for testimony.
And if I do it?
We'll make sure you go free.
(REBEL SOLDIERS
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
DRAVEN: Captain Andor.
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT
OVER PA)
I'm K-2SO.
I'm a reprogrammed Imperial droid.
I remember you.
I see the Council is
sending you with us to Jedha.
Apparently so.
That is a bad idea. I think so,
and so does Cassian.
What do I know?
My specialty is just
- strategic analysis.
- (KEYBOARD CLACKING)
Galen Erso is vital to
the Empire's weapons program.
Forget what you heard in there.
There will be no extraction.
You find him...
you kill him.
Then and there.
MALE DISPATCHER: (OVER RADIO)
Shuttle number LMTR-20.
Prepare for takeoff while
we check your authorization.
CASSIAN: You met K-2?
Charming.
He tends to say
whatever comes into his circuits.
It's a byproduct of the reprogram.
Why does she get a blaster and I don't?
- What?
- I know how to use it.
That's what I'm afraid of. Give it to me.
We're going to Jedha.
That's a war zone.
That's not the point. Where'd you get it?
I found it.
K-2SO: I find that answer
vague and unconvincing.
Trust goes both ways.
You're letting her keep it?
Would you like to know the probability
of her using it against you?
It's high.
Let's get going.
It's very high.
- (BUTTONS CLICKING)
- (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
SAW: (SHOUTING) Lies!
Deceptions!
Let's see it.
"Bodhi Rook. Cargo pilot. "
- Local boy, huh?
- Uh-huh.
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
BODHI: (CHUCKLES)
Okay. I can hear you.
He didn't capture me. I came
here myself. I defected.
I defected.
SAW: Every day, more lies.
(GRUNTS)
Lies? Would I risk everything for a lie?
No, we don't have time for this.
I have to speak to Saw Gerrera
before it's too late.
(EXHALES) Okay.
Sorry, you're...
Um...
(STAMMERS) That's for you.
And I gave it to them.
They did not find it!
I gave it to them.
Uh, Galen Erso.
He told me to find you.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(GRUNTS)
Bor Gullet.
Uh, Bor Gullet?
What? Wait!
(GRUNTING)
Galen Erso sent me!
He told me to find you.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
TARKIN: Most unfortunate about
the security breach on Jedha,
Director Krennic.
After so many setbacks
and delays, and now this.
(SIGHS)
We've heard word of rumors
circulating through the city.
Apparently, you've lost
a rather talkative cargo pilot.
If the Senate gets wind of our project,
countless systems
will flock to the Rebellion.
When the battle station is
finished, Governor Tarkin...
the Senate will be of little concern.
When has become now,
Director Krennic.
The Emperor will tolerate
no further delay.
You have made time
an ally of the Rebellion.
I suggest we solve
both problems simultaneously...
with an immediate test of the weapon.
Failure will find you explaining why
to a far less patient audience.
I will not fail.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
What's the matter, Jyn?
You look frightened.
I'll always protect you.
Stardust.
Don't ever change.
LYRA: Trust.
Galen.
- (DOOR OPENS)
- (GASPS)
CASSIAN: We're coming into orbit.
You have controls.
That's Jedha.
Or what's left of it.
We find Saw, we find your father.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
What's with the Destroyer?
It's because of
your old friend, Saw Gerrera.
He's been attacking
the cargo shipments.
What are they bringing in?
It's what are they taking out.
Kyber crystal. All they can get.
We wondered why
they were stripping the temple.
Now we know.
It's the fuel for the weapon.
The weapon your father's building.
Maybe we should leave
target practice behind.
Are you talking about me?
She's right. We need to blend in.
Stay with the ship.
I can blend in. I'm an Imperial droid.
The city is under Imperial occupation.
Half the people here
wanna reprogram you.
The other half wanna
put a hole in your head.
I'm surprised
you're so concerned with my safety.
I'm not.
I'm just worried they might
miss you and hit me.
Doesn't sound so bad to me.
- (BOR GULLET GRUNTING)
- (BODHI BREATHING HEAVILY)
SAW: Bor Gullet can feel your thoughts.
No lie is safe.
(GASPING, WHIMPERING)
What have you really
brought me, cargo pilot?
Bor Gullet will know the truth.
The unfortunate side effect
is that one tends...
to lose one's mind.
No! (WHIMPERING)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
- (JYN GRUNTS)
- Hey.
You just watch yourself.
Wait. No, no.
Sorry, sir.
We don't want any trouble. Sorry.
Come on. Come on.
MALE IMPERIAL OFFICER:
Citizens of Jedha.
You must come forward with information
of the location
of this missing cargo pilot.
A reward of 600 credits
for the information shall be awarded.
CASSIAN: I had a contact.
One of Saw's Rebels.
But he's just gone missing.
His sister will be looking for him.
The temple's been destroyed,
but she'll be there waiting.
We'll give her your name
and hope that gets us
a meeting with Saw.
Hope?
Yeah. Rebellions are built on hope.
STORMTROOPER 3:
Hands where I can see them.
Get over there.
Show me some identification.
Check inside.
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
Is this all because of your pilot?
CHIRRUT: May the Force
of others be with you.
Wait for me.
CHIRRUT: May the Force
of others be with you.
May the Force of others be with you.
Would you trade that necklace
for a glimpse into your future?
Yes.
I'm speaking to you.
I'm Chirrut îmwe.
How did you know
I was wearing a necklace?
For that answer, you must pay.
What do you know
about kyber crystals?
My father, he...
He said they powered
the Jedi's lightsabers.
Jyn.
Come on. Let's go.
The strongest stars
have hearts of kyber.
Let's go.
We're not here to make friends.
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
Who are they?
The Guardians of the Whills.
Protectors of the Kyber Temple.
But there's nothing left to protect.
So now they're just
causing trouble for everybody.
You seem awfully tense all of a sudden.
We have to hurry.
This town is ready to blow.
MALE IMPERIAL ANNOUNCER:
Citizens of the Empire...
Imperial forces tirelessly fight
Saw Gerrera's reign of terror...
over the people of this beloved city.
Truth and justice
are the tools of the Empire.
(ANNOUNCEMENT
CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY)
(SPEAKS ALIEN LANGUAGE)
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
Tell me you have a backup plan.
- (GUNFIRE)
- (ALL SCREAMING)
Incoming!
- (GUNFIRE)
- (INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Looks like we found Saw's rebels.
Up there!
(CHILD WAILING)
Jyn, no!
(WOMAN SHOUTS)
Hit the terrorist.
Get out of there!
(SHOUTS)
(MAN SCREAMS)
(SHOUTING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
Kyber... (SPEAKS ALIEN LANGUAGE)
Come on!
(GUNFIRE AND
SHOUTING CONTINUE)
This way!
Cassian!
(BATON CLICKING)
(JYN GRUNTING)
(STORMTROOPER GROANS)
Did you know that wasn't me?
Yeah. Of course.
I thought I told you to stay on the ship.
You did. But I thought it was boring,
and you were in trouble.
There were a lot of explosions...
- for two people blending in.
- STORMTROOPER: Freeze!
You're right.
I should just wait on the ship.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
STORMTROOPER:
Halt. Stop right there.
Where are you taking these prisoners?
- These are prisoners.
- Yes. Where are you taking them?
I am taking them
to imprison them in prison.
- He's taking us to... (GROANS)
- Quiet!
And there's a fresh one
if you mouth off again.
- We'll take them from here.
- That's okay.
If you could just point me
in the right direction,
I can take them, I'm sure.
- I've taken them this far.
- Hey, wait a second.
- Take them away.
- Wait.
You can't take them away.
You. Stay here.
We need to check your diagnostics.
Diagnostics?
I'm capable of running
my own diagnostics,
thank you very much.
CHIRRUT: Let them pass in peace.
Let them pass in peace.
The Force is with me.
And I am with the Force.
And I fear nothing.
For all is as the Force wills it.
Hey, stop right there.
He's blind.
Is he deaf?
I said stop right there!
(WEAPONS COCKING)
(STORMTROOPERS GROANING)
Is your foot all right?
(GROANING CONTINUES)
(JYN GASPS)
You almost shot me.
You're welcome.
Clear of hostiles.
- One hostile.
- He's with us.
They're all right.
Thanks.
Cassian, I'm sorry about the slap.
Go back to the ship. Wait for my call.
Is he a Jedi?
There are no Jedi here anymore.
Only dreamers like this fool.
The Force did protect me.
I protected you.
Can you get us to Saw Gerrera?
(SHOUTING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
Can't you see?
We are no friends of the Empire.
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
Anyone who kills me or my friends
will answer to Saw Gerrera.
Because I'm the daughter of Galen Erso.
(GRUNTING)
Are you kidding me? I'm blind.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- (SHOUTING)
- (GROANS)
(MUSIC AND ALIEN CHATTER)
CHIRRUT: I'm one with the Force,
the Force is with me.
I'm one with the Force,
You pray?
the Force is with me.
Really?
I'm one with the Force,
the Force is with me.
He's praying for the door to open.
It bothers him because
he knows it's possible.
(SNICKERING)
Baze Malbus was once the most
devoted Guardian of us all.
I'm beginning to think the Force and I
have different priorities.
CHIRRUT: Relax, Captain.
We've been in worse cages
than this one.
This is the first for me.
There is more than
one sort of prison, Captain.
I sense that you carry yours
wherever you go.
(BAZE SCOFFS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE)
SAW: Jyn.
Is it really you?
I can't believe it!
Must be quite a surprise.
Are we not still friends?
The last time I saw you,
you gave me a knife
and loaded blaster...
and told me to wait
in a bunker till daylight.
I knew you were safe.
You left me behind.
You were already
the best soldier in my cadre.
- I was 16!
- I was protecting you!
You dumped me!
You were the daughter of
an Imperial science officer.
People were starting to figure that out.
People who wanted to
use you as a hostage.
Not a day goes by...
that I don't think of you.
But today...
of all days...
(BREATH TREMBLING)
It's a trap.
Isn't it? (LAUGHS)
What?
The pilot.
The message.
All of it.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Did they send you?
Did you come here...
to kill me?
There's not much of me left.
The Alliance wants my father.
They think he sent you
a message about a weapon.
I guess they think by sending me,
you might actually help them out.
So what is it that you want, Jyn?
They wanted an introduction,
they've got it.
I'm out now.
Rest of you can do what you want.
You care not about the cause?
The cause?
Seriously?
The Alliance...
the rebels, whatever it is
you're calling yourself these days...
all it's ever brought me is pain.
You can stand to see the Imperial flag
reign across the galaxy?
It's not a problem if you don't look up.
I have something to show you.
Come.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
The Emperor is awaiting my report.
One would hope that he and Lord Vader
might've been here
for such an occasion.
And I thought it prudent to save you
from any potential embarrassment.
Your concern's hardly warranted.
If saying it would only make it so.
All Imperial forces
have been evacuated...
and I stand ready to destroy
the entire moon.
That won't be necessary.
We need a statement, not a manifesto.
The Holy City will be enough for today.
Target Jedha City.
Prepare single reactor ignition.
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
- PTERRO: Sir, we're in position...
- Fire!
Commence primary ignition.
Who's the one in the next cell?
BAZE: What?
Where?
An Imperial pilot.
- Pilot?
- BAZE: I'm gonna kill him!
- No, no. No, wait!
- Come here!
No!
Back off! Back off!
CASSIAN: Okay, okay.
- Are you the pilot?
- (GROANING SOFTLY)
Hey. Hey. Are you the pilot?
The shuttle pilot?
Pilot?
What's wrong with him?
Galen Erso.
You know that name?
I brought the message. I'm the pilot.
(CHUCKLES SLOWLY)
I'm the pilot.
Okay. Good.
Now where is Galen Erso?
ANNOUNCER: (OVER PA) Stand by.
SAW: This is the message I was sent.
Saw, if you are watching this...
then perhaps there's a chance
to save the Alliance.
Perhaps there's a chance
to explain myself...
and, though I don't dare
hope for too much...
a chance for Jyn, if she's alive...
if you can possibly find her...
to let her know that my love
for her has never faded...
and how desperately I've missed her.
(BEEPS)
Jyn, my Stardust...
I can't imagine what you think of me.
When I was taken,
I faced some bitter truths.
I was told that soon enough
Krennic would have you as well.
As time went by...
I knew that you were either dead...
or so well hidden that
he would never find you.
I knew if I had refused to work,
if I took my own life...
it would only be a matter of time
before Krennic realized...
he no longer needed me
to complete the project.
So I did the one thing nobody expected.
I lied.
I learned to lie.
I played the part of a beaten man
resigned to the sanctuary of his work.
I made myself indispensable...
and all the while, I laid
the groundwork of my revenge.
We call it the Death Star.
There is no better name...
and the day is coming soon
when it will be unleashed.
I've placed a weakness
deep within the system...
a flaw so small and powerful,
they will never find it.
But, Jyn...
Jyn, if you're listening, my beloved...
so much of my life has been wasted.
I try to think of you only
in the moments when I'm strong...
because the pain of
not having you with me...
your mother, our family.
The pain of that loss
is so overwhelming...
I risk failing even now.
It's just so hard not to think of you.
Think of where you are...
my Stardust.
Saw...
the reactor module, that's the key.
That's the place I've laid my trap.
It's well hidden and unstable.
One blast to any part of it
will destroy the entire station.
You'll need the plans...
the structural plans for the Death Star,
to find the reactor.
I know there's a complete
engineering archive...
in the data vault
at the Citadel Tower on Scarif.
Any pressurized explosion
to the reactor module...
will set off a chain reaction
that will destroy the entire station.
(RUMBLING)
(SPEAKING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
Go, go!
(SHOUTING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
K-2, K-2! Where are you?
K-2SO: There you are.
I'm standing by as you requested...
although there's a problem
on the horizon.
There's no horizon.
Locate our position.
Bring that ship in here, now!
Where are you going?
I gotta find Jyn.
Get the pilot, we need him!
All right.
I'll get the pilot.
Pilot.
No, no, no!
Let's go.
Jyn!
Hey.
We gotta go.
I know where your father is.
Go with him, Jyn.
You must go!
Come with us.
I will run no longer.
- Come on.
- But you must save yourself.
- Go!
There's no time!
SAW: Save the Rebellion!
Save the dream.
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
(SHOUTING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
Oh, it's beautiful.
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
Chirrut, let's go!
Come on!
Let's get out of here!
(ENGINES ROARING)
CASSIAN: Get us out of here!
Punch it!
I'm not very optimistic about our odds.
Not now, K.
(ENGINES ROARING)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(DECOMPRESSION HISS)
(RUMBLING)
Come on!
Punch it.
I haven't completed my calculations.
I'll make them for you.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
I believe I owe you
an apology, Director Krennic.
Your work exceeds all expectations.
And you'll tell the Emperor as much?
I will tell him that his patience
with your misadventures...
has been rewarded with a weapon
that will bring a swift end
to the Rebellion.
And that that was only an inkling
of its destructive potential.
I will tell him that I will be
taking control over the weapon...
I first spoke of years ago
effective immediately.
(SCOFFS)
We stand here amidst my achievement.
Not yours!
I'm afraid the recent security breaches...
have laid bare your inadequacies
as a military director.
The breaches have been filled.
Jedha has been silenced.
You think this pilot acted alone?
He was dispatched from
the installation on Eadu...
Galen Erso's facility.
Oh, we'll see about this.
BASTEREN: A coded message
from Captain Andor, sir.
"Weapon confirmed. "
"Jedha destroyed. "
"Mission target located
on Eadu, please advise. "
Destroyed?
Proceed.
Tell him my orders still stand.
Tell him to proceed with haste...
and keep to the plan.
We have no idea
what he's building for the Empire.
We have to kill Galen Erso
while we have the chance.
- (WHOOSHING)
- (INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
CHIRRUT: Baze, tell me.
All of it?
The whole city?
Tell me.
All of it.
CASSIAN: Understood.
(RADIO CONTROLS BEEP)
Set course for Eadu.
Setting course for Eadu.
Is that where my father is?
I think so.
So you're Galen's daughter?
You know him?
I am Bodhi, the pilot.
You brought the message.
Yes.
Your father...
he said I could get right by myself.
He said I could make it right...
if I was brave enough...
to listen to what was in my heart.
Do something about it.
Guess it was too late.
It wasn't too late.
Seems pretty late to me.
JYN: No.
We can beat the people who did this.
My father's message, I've seen it.
They call it the Death Star.
But they have no idea...
there's a way to defeat it.
You're wrong about my father.
He did build it.
Because he knew
they'd do it without him.
My father made a choice.
He sacrificed himself for the Rebellion.
He's rigged a trap inside it.
That's why he sent you,
to bring that message.
Where is it?
Where's the message?
It was a hologram.
You have that message, right?
Everything happened so fast.
Did you see it?
You don't believe me?
I'm not the one you've got to convince.
I believe her.
That's good to know.
What kind of trap?
You said your father made a trap.
The reactor.
He's placed a weakness there.
He's been hiding it for years.
He said if you can blow the reactor,
the module,
the whole system goes down.
You need to send word to the Alliance.
I've done that.
They have to know
there's a way to destroy this thing.
They have to go to Scarif
to get the plans.
I can't risk sending that.
We're in the heart of Imperial territory.
Then we'll find him and bring him back.
And he can tell them himself.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
NAVIGATOR:
Course set for Eadu, sir.
I'm one with the Force,
the Force is with me.
K-2SO: 20 degrees to the right.
10 degrees up.
Lower, lower, lower. Lower!
Are you sure this is the way?
BODHI: They have
landing trackers here.
They have patrol squadrons.
You've got to stay
in the canyon. Keep it low.
(WARNING SYSTEMS BLARING)
Watch your right!
There's a 26*% chance of failure.
How much farther?
I don't know, I'm not sure.
I never really come this way.
But we're close, we're close. I know that.
Now, there's a 35% chance of failure.
CASSIAN: I don't wanna know.
Thank you!
I understand.
Now! Put it down, now!
The wind.
If you keep going,
you'll be right over the shuttle depot.
- Watch out!
- CASSIAN: K!
(GRUNTING)
Hold on tight!
We're coming down hard!
(ALARMS BLARING)
(ENGINES ROARING)
Try them again.
I am, sir. We...
The signal's gone dead.
DRAVEN: Squadron up.
Target Eadu.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
How about now? Check stabilizers.
Bodhi, where's the lab?
The research facility?
Yeah. Where is it?
It's just over that ridge.
That's a shuttle depot
straight ahead of us.
- You are sure of that?
- Yes.
We'll have to hope
there's still an Imperial ship
left to steal.
Here's what we're doing.
Hopefully the storm keeps up
and keeps us hidden down here.
Bodhi, you're coming with me.
We'll go up the ridge and check it out.
I'm coming with you.
No, your father's message.
We can't risk it. You're the messenger.
That's ridiculous,
we all got the message.
Everyone here knows it.
(GUN CLICKS)
"One blast to the reactor module
"and the whole system goes down. "
That's how you said it,
"The whole system goes down. "
Get to work fixing our comms.
All I want to do right now
is get a handle on what we're up against.
So we're gonna go very small
and very careful up the rise...
and see what's what.
Let's get outta here.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
Does he look like a killer?
No. He has the face of a friend.
Who are you talking about?
Captain Andor.
Why'd you ask that?
What do you mean,
"Does he look like a killer?"
The Force moves darkly
near a creature that's about to kill.
His weapon was
in the sniper configuration.
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT
ECHOING)
No, no, no. We've got to go up.
You can't see much from down there.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT
CONTINUES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTS)
This way.
I'll be right behind you.
Come on.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna follow Jyn.
Her path is clear.
Alone?
Good luck!
I don't need luck. I have you!
(GROANS)
What are they doing?
If Cassian comes back,
we're leaving without them.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
You see Erso out there?
BAZE: We've come too far.
(GROANS)
Patience, my friend.
(PANTING)
That's him.
That's him. Galen, in the dark suit.
Get back down there
and find us a ride outta here.
- Well, what are you doing?
- You heard me.
You said we came up here
just to have a look.
I'm here, I'm looking. Go.
Hurry!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
KRENNIC: Excellent news, Galen.
The battle station is complete.
You must be very proud.
Proud as I can be, Krennic.
Gather your engineers.
I have an announcement.
(PANTING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
Is that all of them?
Yes.
Gentlemen, one of you...
betrayed the Empire.
(MEN GASPING AND EXCLAIMING)
One of you has conspired with a pilot...
to send messages to the Rebellion.
And I urge that traitor...
step forward.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS
CONTINUE)
(MECHANICAL VOICE SPEAKS)
Very well...
I'll consider it a group effort then.
Ready!
- No! No!
- Aim!
And fire!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Krennic, stop!
It was me!
They have nothing to do with it.
Spare them.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Fire!
(MEN GROANING)
(GROANS)
How do I know the weapon is complete?
Let me share with you some details.
(STORMTROOPER SCREAMS)
K-2SO: Cassian.
Cassian, can you hear me?
CASSIAN: I'm here.
You've got it working?
Affirmative, yes.
Although we have a problem.
There's an Alliance squadron
approaching. Clear the area.
No, no, no, no! Tell them to hold off!
Jyn's on that platform.
Jedha...
Saw Gerrera. His band of fanatics...
their Holy City...
the last reminder of the Jedi, gone.
You'll never win.
Now where have I heard that before?
K-2SO: Relay from Captain Andor.
General.
Captain Andor requesting
a delay on squadron support.
Alliance forces on site. Please confirm.
Get the squadron leader on.
Get him on now!
They're already engaged, sir.
(ALARM BLARING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(MEN GROANING)
Jyn. No.
Return fire! To your stations!
Get our fighters in the air now!
Father!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(GROANING)
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
MALE IMPERIAL GUNNER:
Roger that. 3 through 7.
(GUNS FIRING AND EXPLOSIONS)
GUARD: Fall back! Fall back!
Director, we need to evacuate.
(GROANING)
(GUNS FIRING)
(EXHALES)
(MAN SCREAMS)
(MECHANICAL VOICE SPEAKS)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
Papa. Papa, it's me.
It's Jyn.
Jyn?
Stardust.
Papa.
I've seen your message.
The hologram, I've seen it.
It must be destroyed.
I know. I know.
We will.
Jyn.
Look at you.
I have so much to tell you.
(GALEN GROANS SLOWLY)
Papa.
No.
No! Papa.
Papa, come on!
STORMTROOPER:
Over there! Take 'em down.
Come on. Papa. Come on.
Jyn, we gotta go. Come on.
I can't leave him.
Listen to me, he's gone.
Nothing you can do. Come on.
- I can't leave him.
- Come on!
I can't.
Move!
- This way, this way!
- CASSIAN: Down!
(STORMTROOPERS YELLING)
Come on! Come on!
Well done.
You're a rebel now.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
BODHI: Let's go! Let's go!
Come on, let's move!
Come on, let's get out of here!
Move, move, move!
Okay, K-2. Let's go!
Copy that.
(EXPLODING)
BODHI: lon thrusters low until
we've cleared the storm.
K-2SO: Understood.
You lied to me.
You're in shock.
You went up there to kill my father.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
Deny it.
You're in shock and looking
for some place to put it.
I've seen it before.
I bet you have.
They know.
You lied about why we came here
and you lied about why you went up alone.
(SIGHS)
I had every chance to pull the trigger...
but did I?
Did I?
You might as well have.
My father was living proof...
and you put him at risk.
Those were Alliance bombs
that killed him.
I had orders...
orders that I disobeyed.
But you wouldn't understand that.
Orders?
When you know they're wrong?
You might as well be a Stormtrooper.
What do you know?
We don't all have
the luxury of deciding...
when and where we want to
care about something.
Suddenly the Rebellion is real for you.
Some of us live it.
I've been in this fight
since I was 6 years old.
You're not the only one
who lost everything.
Some of us just decided
to do something about it.
You can't talk your way around this.
I don't have to.
Yavin 4.
Make sure they know
we're coming in with a stolen ship.
Anybody else?
(SIGHS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR HISSING)
My lord, Director Krennic...
has arrived.
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(DRAINING SOUND)
(RASPY BREATHING)
(DARTH VADER THEME PLAYING)
Director Krennic.
Lord Vader.
You seem unsettled.
No...
just pressed for time.
There's a great many things to attend to.
My apologies.
You do have
a great many things to explain.
I delivered the weapon
the Emperor requested.
I deserve an audience...
to make certain that
he understands its remarkable...
potential.
Its power to create problems
has certainly been confirmed.
A city destroyed...
an Imperial facility openly attacked.
It was Governor Tarkin
that suggested the test.
You were not summoned here
to grovel, Director Krennic.
No...
There is no Death Star.
The Senate has been informed...
that Jedha was destroyed
in a mining disaster.
Yes, my lord.
I expect you not to rest until
you can assure the Emperor...
that Galen Erso has not compromised
this weapon in any way.
So I'm still in command?
You'll speak to the Emperor about...
(CHOKING)
Be careful not to choke
on your aspirations, Director.
(GASPING)
PAMLO: We must scatter the fleet.
We have no recourse but to surrender.
BAIL: Are we really talking
about disbanding something...
that we've worked so hard to create?
We can't just give in!
We joined an alliance,
not a suicide pact.
We've only now managed
to gather our forces.
Gather our forces?
General Draven's already
blown up an Imperial base.
A decision needed to be made!
PAMLO: If it's war you want...
you'll fight alone.
If that's how it's going,
why have an alliance at all?
If she's telling the truth,
we need to act now!
Councilors, please.
It is simple.
The Empire has the means
of mass destruction...
the Rebellion does not.
A Death Star. This is nonsense.
What reason
would my father have to lie?
What benefit would it bring him?
To lure our forces into a final battle
to destroy us once and for all.
VASPAR: Risk everything?
Based on what?
The testimony of a criminal?
The dying words of her father,
an Imperial scientist?
JEBEL: But don't forget
the Imperial pilot.
My father gave his life so that
we may have a chance to defeat this.
So you've told us.
If the Empire has this kind of power,
what chance do we have?
What chance do we have?
The question is "what choice. "
Run, hide...
plead for mercy, scatter your forces.
You give way to an enemy this evil
with this much power...
and you condemn the galaxy
to an eternity of submission.
- The time to fight is now!
- ALL: Yes.
Every moment you waste
is another step closer
to the ashes of Jedha.
COUNCIL MEMBER 1:
What is she proposing?
COUNCIL MEMBER 2:
Just let the girl speak.
Send your best troops to Scarif.
(CROWD MURMURING)
Send the rebel fleet if you have to.
You need to capture
the Death Star plans
if there's any hope of destroying it.
(COUNCIL MUTTERING)
You're asking us to invade
an Imperial installation...
based on nothing but hope.
Rebellions are built on hope.
There is no hope.
I say we fight.
I say the Rebellion is finished!
(ALL MURMURING)
I'm sorry, Jyn.
Without the full support of the Council...
(SIGHS) the odds are too great.
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
(ALL MURMURING)
REBEL ANNOUNCER:
General Syndulla,
please report to the briefing room.
You don't look happy.
They prefer to surrender.
And you?
She wants to fight.
So do I. We all do.
The Force is strong.
I'm not sure four of us is quite enough.
How many do we need?
What are you talking about?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
They were never gonna believe you.
I appreciate the support.
But I do.
I believe you.
We'd like to volunteer.
Some of us...
Well, most of us...
we've all done terrible things
on behalf of the Rebellion.
Spies...
saboteurs, assassins.
Everything I did, I did for the Rebellion.
And every time I walked away...
from something I wanted to forget...
I told myself it was
for a cause that I believed in.
A cause that was worth it.
Without that, we're lost.
Everything we've done
would have been for nothing.
I couldn't face myself if I gave up now.
None of us could.
BODHI: It won't be comfortable.
It'd be a bit cramped, but we'd all fit.
We could go.
Okay. Gear up.
Grab anything that's not nailed down.
(REBELS TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
CASSIAN: Go, go, go!
K-2SO: Jyn.
I'll be there for you.
Cassian said I had to.
I'm not used to people sticking around
when things go bad.
Welcome home.
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT
OVER PA)
- (CHEERFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
May the Force be with us.
(SCATTERED APPLAUSE,
LAUGHTER)
DISPATCHER: Cargo shuttle,
read back please.
What's going on out there?
That ship's off-limits.
No one's supposed to be on board
until further instructions.
Yes, yes, we are.
Affirmative.
That's an impounded Imperial ship.
What's your call sign, pilot?
- Um...
- We have to go.
It's, um...
Say something.
Come on.
Rogue.
Rogue One.
DISPATCHER: Rogue One?
- There is no Rogue One!
- (BEEPING)
Well, there is now.
Rogue One, pulling away.
Pulling away.
Despite what the others say,
war is inevitable.
Yes, I agree.
I must return to Alderaan
to inform my people
that there will be no peace.
We will need every advantage.
Your friend...
the Jedi.
He served me well
during the Clone Wars...
and has lived in hiding
since the Emperor's purge.
Yes, I will send for him.
You will need someone you can trust.
I would trust her with my life.
- Captain Antilles.
- Senator.
I have a mission for you, sir.
(SHIP WHOOSHING)
BODHI: Okay. We're coming in.
There's a planet-wide defensive shield...
with a single main entry gate.
This shuttle should be equipped with
an access code that allows us through.
Assuming the Empire hasn't
logged it as overdue.
And if they have?
Then they shut the gate.
And we're all annihilated
in the cold, dark vacuum of space.
Not me.
I can survive in space.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
BODHI: Okay.
Here goes.
Cargo shuttle SW-0608
requesting a landing pad.
GATE OFFICER:
Cargo shuttle SW-0608,
you're not listed on the arrival schedule.
BODHI: Acknowledged, Gate Control.
We were rerouted
from Eadu flight station.
Transmitting clearance code now.
Transmitting.
GATE OFFICER:
Cargo shuttle, SW-0608...
- you are cleared for entry.
- Yes!
- (SIGHS)
- Impressive.
(CHUCKLES)
I'll tell the others.
Okay.
SCARIF BASE ANNOUNCER: Tractor
beam test in bays 2 through 8.
Tractor beam test in bays 2 through 8.
GATE OFFICER: SW-0608,
cleared for Landing Pad 9.
Acknowledge, please.
BODHI: SW-0608 proceeding
to LP 9 as instructed.
CASSIAN: Main building
down there, what is it?
BODHI: That's the Citadel Tower.
They keep all the Imperial
structural archives up there.
If the plans are anywhere,
they'll be there.
CASSIAN: And the dish
at the top, what's it for?
I guess it takes a lot of signal
to send those data files out.
Landing track, engaged.
Landing track locked.
We're landing.
We're coming in.
Saw Gerrera used to say...
one fighter with a sharp stick
and nothing left to lose can take the day.
They've no idea we're coming.
They've no reason to expect us.
If we can make it to the ground,
we'll take the next chance.
And the next. On and on until we win...
or the chances are spent.
The Death Star plans are down there.
Cassian, K-2, and I will find them.
We'll find a way to find them.
Melshi...
Pao...
Baze, Chirrut...
you'll take the main squad.
Move east and get wide of the ship.
Find a position between
here and the tower.
Once you get to the best spot...
light the place up.
Make 10 men feel like 100.
(MEN AGREEING)
And get those troopers away from us.
What should I do?
Keep the engine running.
You're our only way outta here.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
LANDING PAD OFFICER:
Cargo shuttle SW-0608...
be prepared to receive inspection team.
Ready?
Hello.
Hey.
Oh, you're probably
looking for a manifest?
That would be helpful.
It's just down here.
IMPERIAL OFFICER: Director Krennic,
we are entering the Scarif shield gate.
General Ramda has been
informed of your arrival.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
BAZE: Good luck...
little sister.
Go! Go now! You're clear!
MELSHI: All right, let's go!
Come on. Move, move, move.
ANNOUNCER:
925-H to transport control.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
I've got a bad feeling about...
- K!
- (WHISPERS) Quiet!
What?
We need a map.
Well, I'm sure there's one
just lying about.
You know what you have to do.
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT
OVER PA)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
One per pad.
Pick your spot.
We wanna draw them out.
I'll call the timing. Go!
STORMTROOPER 5:
Hey, did you hear the rumors?
STORMTROOPER 6: Yeah, the T-15s
have been marked obsolete.
STORMTROOPER 5: Oh boy,
it's about time for that.
Hey!
(GROANING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(BEEPING)
- What the...
- (GRUNTS)
Director, what brings you to Scarif?
Galen Erso.
I want every dispatch,
every transmission he has ever sent...
called up for inspection.
RAMDA: All of them?
Yes, all of them.
Get started.
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
- (MOUSE DROID BEEPING)
(MECHANICAL WHIRRING)
K.
Our optimal route to the data vault
places only 89 Stormtroopers
in our path.
We will make it
no more than 33% of the way
before we are killed.
Melshi, talk to me.
Ready. Ready. Standing by.
Light it up.
(STORMTROOPER GROANS)
Come on.
(EXPLOSIONS ECHOING)
Are we blind?
Deploy the garrison!
Move!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
Troopers!
Troopers! Troopers on the left.
Get in! Get in!
(ALARM BLARING)
(YELLING)
(MAN GROANS)
ROMODI: Sir, it's Scarif base.
They're reporting a Rebel incursion.
I want to speak with Director Krennic.
He's there, sir. On Scarif.
The original plans for this station
are kept there, are they not?
They are.
Prepare for the jump to hyperspace
and inform Lord Vader.
Can we help you?
That won't be necessary.
(GROANS)
Senator!
Stop right there, Private.
Let him speak.
Intercepted Imperial
transmission, ma'am.
Rebels on Scarif.
I need to speak with Admiral Raddus.
He's returned to his ship.
He's going to fight.
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
No!
(GROANS)
REBEL ANNOUNCER: Attention,
all flight personnel,
please report to
your commanders immediately.
All flight personnel,
please report to
your commanders immediately.
We have been redirected to Scarif.
Pilots, you'll be briefed
by your squadron leaders en route.
May the Force be with you.
Scarif? They're going to Scarif?
Why does nobody
ever tell me anything, R2?
(R2-D2 BEEPING)
Move, move, move!
(SHOUTING)
Forward! Forward!
Keep drawing them out!
(GROANS)
OFFICER 1: Pad 12, report to ground.
Coming in on our flank.
We need numbers.
OFFICER 2: Pad 14,
what's going on down there?
Status please.
All pads report in immediately.
OFFICER 3: Oh, no.
We have rebels everywhere!
We're taking fire!
Pad 12, Pad 14 request assistance.
This is Pad 2. Pad 2.
I spot 40 rebels heading west on Pad 2.
Get on there. Tell him you're pinned
down by rebels on Pad 5.
TONC: This is Pad 5!
We're being overrun! Help us!
Pad 12, Pad 10, Pad 8, please confirm.
Confirm and report.
Get reinforcements down
to Pad 5 immediately!
CASSIAN: This is not working, K!
Right hand.
(MEN GROANING, YELLING)
Baze!
- Baze!
- What?
Run!
(GRUNTING)
Karabast! AT-AT!
Move!
(YELLING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS)
This is Admiral Raddus
of the Rebel Alliance.
All squadron leaders, report in.
Admiral, this is Blue Leader standing by.
This is Gold Leader standing by.
This is Red Leader standing by.
Sir, those are rebel ships.
Get Admiral Gorin, immediately!
Director, the rebel fleet,
it's amassing outside the shield.
Lock down the base. Lock it down.
- And close the shield?
- Do it!
Red and Gold Squadrons,
attack formations.
Defend the fleet.
Blue Squadron, get to the surface
before they close that gate.
MERRICK: Copyyou, Admiral.
Blue Squadron, on me!
Copy, Blue Leader.
- Copy, Blue Leader.
- We won't have long.
Close the field aperture now! Close it!
Come on, come on, come on!
Pull up!
(SCREAMING)
(GUNS FIRING)
The rebel fleet has arrived.
What?
There's fighting on the beach.
They've locked down the base.
They've closed the shield gate.
What does that mean?
We're trapped?
We could transmit the plans
to the rebel fleet.
We'd have to get a signal up
to tell them it's coming.
It's the size of the data files.
That's the problem.
They'll never get through.
Someone has to
take that shield gate down.
Bodhi. Bodhi, can you hear me?
Bodhi, tell me you're out there.
Bodhi?
BODHI: I'm here.
I was standing by.
They've started fighting.
The base is on lockdown.
I know. Listen to me.
The rebel fleet is up there.
You've gotta tell them to
blow a hole in the shield gate...
so we can transmit the plans.
Wait. I can't. I'm not hooked
into the comms tower.
We're not tied in.
It's the only way
we're getting them out of here.
Find a way!
Cover our backs.
You'll need this.
You wanted one, right?
Your behavior, Jyn Erso,
is continually unexpected.
Jyn. Come on.
(YELLING CONTINUES)
Sa'kalla!
Fire on my command.
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
Look!
(REBELS CHEERING)
(LAUGHING)
Get ready. We're gonna have
to go out there.
What are you doing?
They've closed the shield gate.
We're stuck here.
But the rebel fleet are pulling in.
We just have to get a signal
strong enough to get through to them...
and let them know
that we're trapped down here.
For that, we have to connect
to the communications tower.
Now, I can patch us in over here,
the landing pad.
But you have to get on the radio.
Get one of the guys out there
to find a master switch.
Get them to activate the connection
between us and that comms tower.
Okay?
Then go!
What's going on
down there, Lieutenant?
Unknown, sir.
We can't raise them.
All rebel frequencies are blocked.
Keep trying.
Engage those Star Destroyers
and let's start probing that shield!
Yes, sir!
REBEL PILOT: We're going in.
Stay with me.
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALIEN SHRIEK)
K-2SO: Schematic bank,
data tower two.
How do I find that?
Searching.
I can locate the tape,
but you'll need to use
the handles for extraction.
What am I supposed to do with this?
Whoa!
Well, finally.
Wait! Stop!
The rebels, they went over there.
CASSIAN: K, what's going on out there?
There's one.
Ah, well.
(STORMTROOPERS GRUNTING)
Come on!
Red Leader, this is Gold Leader.
We're starting our attack run
on the shield gate.
Keep it tight, and watch out
for those towers.
More fighters. Form out at six-five.
Sir, enemy fighters coming in.
TONC: Melshi! Melshi, come in.
Are you there?
Bodhi sent a signal from here.
He's patching us in.
But you guys have to open up
a line for the tower.
How? Please advise.
There's a master switch
at the base of the comm tower.
Master switch? Describe.
What are we looking for?
What does it look like?
The master switch? Where is it?
MERRICK: U-wings, reinforce
those troops on the beach.
All fighters, on me.
We have to shield them from air attack.
Troop reinforcements. Here we go.
- For Jedha!
- (ALL YELLING)
We're having no effect on that shield.
How much more can that thing take?
Stick close, Red Five.
Where are you goin'?
RED FIVE: They're all overme.
I'm trying to lose them!
This is Red Five! I need help!
"Hyperspace tracking.
Navigational systems. "
Two screens down.
"Structural engineering. " Open that one.
PILOT 1: I've got one on my tail!
PILOT 2: I'm on him!
(YELLING CONTINUES)
Project code names: "Stellarsphere,
Mark Omega, Pax Aurora. "
(GRUNTS)
"War-Mantle, Cluster Prism,
Blacksaber. "
What?
"Stardust. "
That's it.
How do you know that?
I know because it's me.
Hey, you! Identify yourself.
- I can...
- (GROANS)
Incoming fire! Get cover!
(YELLING)
CASSIAN: K, we need the file
for Stardust.
Stardust.
That's it.
- (SHUTTING DOWN)
- K?
Climb.
You can still send the plans to the fleet.
If they open the shield gate...
you can broadcast from the tower.
Locking the vault door now.
K?
K!
- Goodbye.
- K!
Sir, unauthorized access
at the data vault.
What?
It's just come in, sir.
Send my guard squadron into battle.
Two men with me, now.
Get that beach under control!
CASSIAN: Bodhi, are you there?
Did you call the fleet?
I can't get to the shuttle.
I can't plug in.
You have to. They have to hit that gate.
If the shield's open,
we can send the plans.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(BODHI GROANING)
PILOT: General, behind you!
(BEEPING)
(YELLING)
(SHOUTING)
Step back.
We're going down!
Come on!
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
Melshi, Melshi.
Come in, please.
I'm tied in at my end.
I just need an open line.
(COUGHS) Hang on.
The master switch.
It's over near that console.
I'm going!
(GROANING)
I've got it!
Careful!
You okay?
Jyn!
(GROANS)
I'm one with the Force,
the Force is with me.
Chirrut!
(MECHANICAL VOICE GRUNTING)
I'm one with the Force
and the Force is with me.
I'm one with the Force,
the Force is with me.
I'm one with the Force...
and the Force is with me.
I'm one with the Force,
Chirrut! Come back!
I'm one with the Force...
Yes!
Keep going! Keep going!
(SCREAMS)
Cassian!
(THUDS)
Chirrut! Come! Come with me!
Chirrut!
(PANTING)
Chirrut.
Don't go. Don't go.
I'm here, I'm here.
It's okay.
It's okay. Look for the Force.
Chirrut.
And you will always find me.
The Force is with me
and I'm one with the Force.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Deflector shields down to 50*%!
We're sustaining heavy damage!
There's no turning back now!
We have to press the attack!
GOLD LEADER: Hit that opening!
GOLD NINE:
We see it, Gold Leader.
lon torpedoes away!
(ENGINE SHUTTING DOWN)
IMPERIAL COMMANDER:
What's happening?
We've lost engine power, sir.
That Star Destroyer's disabled.
This is Rogue One calling
any Alliance ships that can hear me.
Is there anybody out there?
This is Rogue One.
Come in, over!
This is Admiral Raddus,
Rogue One. We hear you.
(LAUGHS)
We have the plans.
They found the Death Star plans.
They have to transmit them
from the communications tower.
You have to take down the shield gate.
It's the only way
they're gonna get them through.
Call up a Hammerhead corvette.
I have an idea.
Stand by, Rogue One. We're on it.
This is for you, Galen.
(YELLING CONTINUES)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
The Force is with me,
and I'm one with the Force.
(WEAPONS FIRING)
(MECHANICAL VOICES GRUNTING)
(JYN GRUNTS)
Corvette Five, locked on target!
Prepare for impact.
(GUNS FIRING)
(GRUNTING)
Sublight thrusters, full power!
(WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTS)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
Reset antenna alignment.
(ALARMS BLARING)
(THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING)
Reverse engines! Full power!
(MEN GROANING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Antenna aligned.
Ready to transmit.
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(STRAINING)
Who are you?
You know who I am.
I'm Jyn Erso.
Daughter of Galen and Lyra.
You've lost.
Oh, I have, have I?
My father's revenge.
He built a flaw in the Death Star.
He put a fuse in the middle
of your machine...
and I've just told the entire galaxy
how to light it.
The shield is up.
Your signal will never reach
the rebel base.
All your ships in the air
will be destroyed.
I lose nothing but time.
You, on the other hand...
die with the Rebellion.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Transmitting.
Transmitting.
Admiral, receiving
transmission from Scarif.
(GRUNTS)
Leave it, leave it!
That's it.
Let's go.
Transmission received.
Admiral, we have the plans!
She did it!
Do you think anybody's listening?
I do.
Someone's out there.
Sir, we're detecting a massive object
emerging from hyperspace.
Sir, shall I begin targeting their fleet?
Lord Vader will handle the fleet.
Target the base at Scarif,
single reactor ignition.
Yes, sir.
Come on.
You may fire when ready.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Commence
primary ignition.
Rogue One, may the Force be with you.
All ships prepare
for jump to hyperspace.
Your father would have been
proud of you, Jyn.
IMPERIAL COMMANDER: The rebel
flagship is disabled, my lord...
but has received transmissions
from the surface.
Prepare a boarding party.
Yes, my lord.
Hurry!
Let's go! We gotta go, now!
Move! Move! Move!
Hurry. Let's go!
Let's go!
It's stuck!
Hey!
Hey! Help!
(ALARM SOUNDING)
(VADER BREATHING)
Open fire!
Help us!
It's jammed!
Pull it!
Here! Here!
Take it! Take it!
Launch!
(ALARM SOUNDING)
Make sure you secure the airlock.
And prepare the escape pods.
Your highness.
The transmission we received.
What is it they've sent us?
Hope.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)